Dr. Sree Lekha

BCom, BEd, MA, PhD

About me

Motivated talented and skilful teacher employing creative teaching strategies driven to inspire students to pursue academic and personal excellence. Consistently strive to create a challenging and engaging learning environment that can effectively articulate information to students and turn them to active leamers. An exceptional track record to transmute workmanship for every three years. Also added credentials to research success with multiple published articles.

personal

Name: Sagurupilla Sree Lekha DOB: 4th December, 1982 Nationality: Indian Status: Married State: Karnatak Mother tongue: Telugu Address: 91st cross, kumarswamy layout, Bangalore 560078

Areas of specialization

ELT (Task Based Language Teaching) •

Interests

Listening Music • Playing Sudoku

Mail

pilla.sreelekha@gmail.com

7013828739

EXPERIENCE

2024-Present | Malla Reddy Engineering College for Women

Asst Professor · Hyderabad ♥

Worked as Asst Professor for BTech Engineering.

2023-2024 BNM Institute Of Technology

Asst Professor · Bangalore 💡

Worked as Asst Professor for BTech Engineering.

2019–2023 | **KL University**

Asst Professor · Andhra Pradesh 💡

Worked as Asst Professor for BTech Engineering.

2009–2019 | Atkinson Senior Secondary School

TEACHER · Andhra Pradesh 9

Worked as a Secondary Grade Teacher [SGT] in Atkinson Senior Secondary School, Vijayawada. Initiated exclusively English classes for high school students.

Studen

2006–2007 St. Johns, Gannavaram

Теаснев · Andhra Pradesh 💡

Worked as Social and English teacher in St. Johns, Gannavaram

DEGREES

2020 Ph. D. English

CERTIFIED · 65 percent- KL. University, Vaddeswaram 🏦

2009 M.A English

CERTIFIED · 60 percent-Nagarjuna University 🏦

2006 **B.Ed**

CERTIFIED · 80 percent-Montessori College, Vijayawada 🚊

2002 **B.Com**

CERTIFIED · 65 percent-K.B.N. College, Vijayawada 🏛

Courses Dealt

- * Course Coordinator for soft skills
- * M.A.English
- * Integrated Professional English.
- * Legal, Professional Communicative skills.
- * Aptitude builder.
- * Verbal Quant and Reasoning.
- * Basic English Grammar.
- * English Proficiency.
- * General English and Legal language

PUBLICATIONS

- Effect of Curriculum Design in Language Learning (Educational Administration Theory and Pratice Scopus Serial No: 11916) - December 2023
- * Recent publication A study on introverts to expedite wth communication techniques for active presentations exclusively in engineering classes indexed open accessed publication
- * A STUDY ON 'LEXICAL APPROACH' IN ENGLISH LANGUAGE TEACHING AND LEARNING.
- FACTORS INFLUENCING THE ENGLISH LANGUAGE SKILLS OF THE HIGHER SECONDARY SCHOOL STUDENTS ON THEIR COMMUNICATION BEHAVIOUR.
- * IMPORTANCE OF CURRICULUM DESIGNING IN TEACHING AND LEARNING.
- * Challenges in English Language Teaching.
- * Eventuating Beneficiary Results Through Flipped Classroom Teaching In Professional Colleges.
- THE NEED OF THE HOUR TO CHANGE THE METHOD OF ELT: A DESCRIPTIVE ANALYSIS OF THE STU-DENTS' LANGUAGE ACQUISITION.
- TEACHING ENGLISH LANGUAGE IN PROFESSIONAL COLLEGES.
- Smart phone: a tool of ICT in language learning.
- * Continuous comprehensive evaluation (CCE) method: A study on its application.
- ACCENTUATING THE INVINCIBLE SPIRIT OF HUMANITY-KAMALA MARKANDAYA'S MIRABAI IN 'SOME INNER FURY'IN THE LIGHT OF ECOFEMINISM.
- Computer science technology:tutor,tool and to explore language teaching

CERTIFICATES & GRANTS

- * Coursera Change Management and Leadership
- * Coursera Mindshift
- * Counsel India Roadmap to become a Successful Counselor
- * Krish Welfare Foundation Solution Focused Brief Therapy
- * AICTE Universal Human Values
- * AICTE Effective Leadership and Excellence in Technical Education
- * AICTE Adobe Digital Creativity skills Delhi NCR
- * AICTE Ancient management and deep reading
- * AICTE Allison 3 certificates
- * MOOC's Saylor 2 certificates
- * TCS ION 10 certificates
- Scholar notification
- * Patents Analysis of how English news channel impacts student for communication learning

BOOKS AND CHAPTERS

- * Stellar Constellations (ELT book author)
- * English Language Teaching (ELT) author
- * Perceptions of Indian youth towards digital India initiatives (book chapter)
- * Eagalism story author.
- * TWIN TRACK APPROACH ON MAINSTREAMING OF GENDER SENSITISATION author.
- * Contemporary Multi-Disciplinary Research Dimension editor
- * Contemporary Multi-Disciplinary Research Dimension book chapter
- * The arc'h' of gratitude author for the story.
- * The passion The poem.

HIGHLIGHTS

- * Resource Person at National Level Conference on NEP 2020
- * Cambridge University Skill Certificate.
- * English Language Teaching (ELT) 2 Books Author.
- Emerging Paradigms in Multidisciplinary Research (Chapter: PERCEPTIONS OF INDIAN YOUTH TOWARDS DIGITAL INDIA INITIATIVES)

PATENTS

Analysis of how English News Channel Impact students for communication learning

SKILLS

- * Event Co-ordination.
- * Public Speaking.
- Student Mentor.
- * Curriculum Developer.
- * School Chronicle Writer.
- Innovative thinking.

CURRICULUM DEALT

OTHER

- * Participation in Global FDP
- * Appeared in Enticing workshops
- * Active involvement in webinars and seminars

VIEW MY CERTIFICATES ON

https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1apHqy2aZx8oceJngLdOnO1RxTvhYjRRq

Sagurupilla Sree Lekha ☑
https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1apHqy2aZx8oceJngLdOnO1RxTvhYjRRq ♀ India,
Karnataka ┗ 7013828739
② pilla.sreelekha@gmail.com